Register of the Russia. Voenno-morskoĭ agent (Germany) Records, 1873-1912
Hoover Institution Archives
Russia Voenno-morskoĭ agent (Germany) Records,
1873-1912
30013
Russia. Voenno-morskoĭ agent (Germany)
4 manuscript boxes (1.7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, orders, and printed matter, relating to Russian-German naval relations, and to Russian purchases of ships, ordnance, and naval equipment from German firms.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1930.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Russia. Voennyi flot--Procurement.; Germany.; Germany--Military relations--Russia.; Russia.; Russia--Military relations--Germany.; Military attaches.
Container List
- Danish Marine Ministry, correspondence with, 1875-78 (Box 1)
- Asbestos inquiry, 1879-1882
- Russian Marine Ministry, information from the German War Office on, 1879-1880
- St. Petersburg Marine Ministry, correspondence with, regarding personal affairs, 1879-1880
- Torpedos, information on, 1873, 1876, 1882
- Marine Ministry, correspondence with, and negotiations of the Naval Attache with foreign firms
- Ijora Works, correspondence and negotiations with the Marine Ministry and the Naval Attache, 1880-81
- Schwarzkopf and the Naxos Union Works, correspondence with, 1880-81
- Chemnitz Works, correspondence with, 1879-1880, 1882
- Artillery orders, 1872-73, 1875-76, 1880
- Nordman's, engineer, invention, 1881
- Hydrographics orders, 1880-82
- Krupp's guns tests, photographs, 1879
- Boiler orders at the Ludv. Loewe Works, Berlin, 1876
- Diving-bell orders at Bernhard Loeb, Berlin, 1877
- Steam torpedo sloops orders at Schicken, Elbing, 1877
- Pyroxiline mill in Russia, correspondence regarding the establishment of a, 1879
- Whitehead torpedo parts from Fiume, 1877
- Factory machinery at Kolpino, 1878
- Machine tools purchase, 1877
- Godffroys Sohn Works, Hamburg, correspondence with, concerning steam boilers, 1879
- Egels Works, Berlin, correspondence with, 1879-1880
- Max Hosse Works, Berlin, correspondence with, 1880
- Krupp Works, Essen, orders, 1880
- Rontchevsky's, Lieutenant, errand, 1880
- German Admiralty, correspondence with, 1880
- Hague, correspondence concerning, 1879-1882
- Copenhagen, correspondence concerning, 1879-1882
- Liverpool orders, 1882
- "Voejevoda" and "Possadnik" destroyers, construction of, at the Schichau Works, Elbing, 1891-92 (Box 2)
- Poustchin, naval engineer, reports of
- Pastuhoff, naval engineer, reports of, 1891-92
- Schichau Works, Elbing, correspondence with, regarding the construction of the cruisers "Kassarsky", "Vojevoda" and "Possadnik", 1890-92
- Werf Conrad shipyard, Haarlem, correspondence with, regarding the construction of barges, 1891-92
- Poretchin, engineer, from Rotterdam, reports of, 1892
- Hope and Company, Amsterdam, correspondence with, 1891-92
- Voith, I. M., Maschinenfabrik, Heidenheim, 1892
- "Bug" and "Dunaj" transports, tests of, 1891-92
- German Admiralty, correspondence regarding the orders of
  - 1890-91
  - 1891
  - 1891-92
- Admiralty abroad, correspondence with individuals and offices in Russia regarding the orders of the, 1891-92
- St. Petersburg Admiralty, correspondence with, 1898
- St. Petersburg Admiralty, correspondence with, 1898 (Box 3)
- Russian shipbuilding and navigation reviews, 1911-12
- Marine Minister Order, 1864
- Supplementary Convention to the Treaty of Commerce and Navigation between Germany and Russia, January 27, 1894, dated July 15, 1904
- Russian Merchant Fleet, register for
- September 1, 1903
- September 1, 1904
- German and foreign navies handbook, 1902
- Consul